Emilie d'Olne

809, Electrical Engineering, South Kensington, Imperial College London, SW7 2AZ, United Kingdom

■ emilie.dolne16@imperial.ac.uk | 🖸 github.com/ed1016 | 🛅 www.linkedin.com/in/emiliedolne | 📚 Emilie d'Olne

Research Interests

My current research focuses on the development of speech enhancement algorithms for hearing aids, with a specific focus on people suffering from dementia-induced hearing impairments. I am part of a clinician project in collaboration with University College London looking at hearing in dementia. My role includes the development of listening tests and assistive technologies for patients affected by dementia syndromes. I am interested in exploiting distributed microphone networks and wearable microphones for enhancement and denoising and am working with techniques such as binaural beamforming and polynomial eigenvalue decomposition (PEVD).

Education

Imperial College London

PhD - Speech and Audio Processing

London, UK 2020 - Present

 Interests in binaural beamforming, dereverberation, speech enhancement, wearable microphone arrays, distributed microphone networks, machine learning, deep learning.

Imperial College London London, UK

MEng - Electrical and Electronic Engineering

2016 - 2020

· Graduated with First Class Honours

• Final year project: "Automatic detection of Alzheimer's Disease using speech"

Athénée Royal Charles Rogier Liège 1

Liège, Belgium

Certificat d'Enseignement Secondaire Supérieur (A-levels equiv.)

2010 - 2016

Experience

Nuance Communications

London, UK

Research Scientist Intern

Summer 2022

• Worked on data augmentation for automatic speech recognition (ASR).

Imperial College IEEE Student Branch

London, UK

Vice-Chair, Treasurer

2021 - Present

• Organisation of technical seminars and workshops, monitoring of the branch's finances.

Imperial College London, Communications and Signal Processing Research Group

London, UK

Postgraduate Student Representative

2021 - Present

• Representing students' interests within the department and at the university.

Imperial College London, Electrical and Electronic Engineering Department

London, UK

Teaching Assistant

2019 - Present

Teaching, development of materials, assessment, and support.

Imperial College London, Speech and Audio Processing Laboratory

London, UK

Research Intern

Summer 2019

• Gaze-directed beamforming for hearing aids in collaboration with Cardiff University.

Publications

- [1] **E. d'Olne**, V. W. Neo, and P. A. Naylor, "Speech Enhancement in Distributed Microphone Arrays Using Polynomial Eigenvalue Decomposition", in *Proc. Eur. Signal Process. Conf. (EUSIPCO)*, Belgrade, Serbia, 2022.
- [2] **E. d'Olne**, V. W. Neo, and P. A. Naylor, "Frame-based space-time covariance matrix estimation for polynomial eigenvalue decomposition-based speech enhancement", in *Proc. Int. Workshop on Acoust. Signal Enhancement (IWAENC)*, Bamberg, Germany, 2022.
- [3] V. W. Neo, **E. d'Olne**, A. H. Moore, and P. A. Naylor, "Fixed beamformer design using polynomial eigenvalue decomposition", in *Proc. Int. Workshop on Acoust. Signal Enhancement (IWAENC)*, Bamberg, Germany, 2022.
- [4] **E. d'Olne**, A. H. Moore, and P. A. Naylor, "Model-based beamforming for wearable microphone arrays", in *Proc. Eur. Signal Process. Conf. (EUSIPCO)*, Dublin, Ireland, 2021.

Awards

2020 Institute of Engineering and Technology (IET) Prize, Imperial College London, EEE Department London, UK
2018, 2019, 2020 Dean's List for Academic Excellence, Imperial College London, EEE Department London, UK

Skills

Technical MATLAB, Python, Bash, TensorFlow, C++, GitHub, Linux, HTML/CSS **Languages** French (bilingual), Spanish (intermediate), German (intermediate)